Evan Rosa Clearance: Public Trust

Current Residence: Washington, DC

Email: erosa26@gmail.com

Cell: (413) 883-9193

#### **EXPERIENCE SUMMARY**

Evan Rosa is a seasoned web marketer, front-end developer, and analytics consultant with experience managing UA architectures and marketing tag strategies. He is a detailed oriented leader that focuses on data accuracy and leveraging resources to understand website usage.

#### **COMPETENCIES**

- Digital Marketing (7 yrs)
- Business Intelligence (BI) Tools (5 yrs)
- Data Analysis (7 yrs)
- Web Software Development (5 yrs)
- Scrum (3yrs)

### TRAINING AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Google Analytics Individual Qualification, 2018
- Adwords Fundamentals, 2018
- General Assembly Front End Web Development Certificate, 2015

### **SUMMARY OF SKILLS, TOOLS, AND TECHNOLOGIES:**

Programming Languages: HTML5 (7 yrs), CSS3 (7 yrs), JavaScript (3 yrs), JQuery (3 yrs), SQL (2 yrs),

node.is (1yrs)

Frameworks: Bootstrap CSS, Zurb Foundation, WordPress

Software/COTS: MS Office Suite (12 yrs), Adobe CS/CC (2 yr), Tableau (3 yrs), SAP

Business Objects (5 yrs), Google Data Studio (2yr), Google Analytics (7 yrs), Google Tag Manager (3 yrs), Google Adwords (5 yrs), Google DoubleClick (3 yrs), Google Webmaster Tools (5yrs), Adobe Analytics (5

yrs), JIRA (3 yrs), Github (3yrs)

Operating Systems: Unix (10 yrs), Windows (10 yrs)

### **EXPERIENCE DETAILS**

# Booz Allen Hamilton, Inc., Staff Technologist Washington, DC

5/2015 - Present

- Current lead web analyst for FDA/CTP anti-tobacco sites creating UA architectures and tagging strategies under the GSA DAP program to ensure 100% accuracy for tracking page views and events across various HHS, CTP, and FDA websites (i.e. Fresh Empire, The Real Cost, and This Free Life, HHS)
- Conduct SEO audits, A/B tests, goal funneling strategies and other data web analysis to implement analytic reports on an ad-hoc, monthly and quarterly basis for website improvements
- Advise client on current trends and best practices in metrics analysis, tools and techniques
- Setup and implement metrics data dashboards using BI tools such as Google Analytics and Tableau
- Conduct multivariate testing and provide data analysis across different sites

Implement steps to migrate website properties from Google Analytics to Universal Analytics

## The American Chemical Society, Web Analytics Associate Washington, DC

12/2010 - 5/2015

- Support the day-to-day operations and administration of the ACS Web Stats Systems
- Assist the Assistant Director, Platform Advertising & Analytics, with scheduled and ad hoc report generation, including the monthly Sales & Marketing Web Usage Report, Annual Web Usage Report and necessary data for editorial board meetings
- Create and maintain advertising reports for the ACS Web Editions platform and C&EN as well as
  advertising reports for ACS managed Web ads on external Websites (Google Search, YouTube, etc.).
   Perform ad hoc advertising reporting queries as needed. Support the Market Development Manager,
  Online Advertising with forecasting and enhanced ad server reporting as needed
- Test and validate Web analytics and reports with each new deployment, product release and/or enhancement in each of the reporting systems, including Literatum, Web Analytics, Google Analytics and Adobe Site Catalyst
- Develop new standard monthly internal reports as necessary, based on feedback from stakeholders within the Publications Division

### Sensei Enterprises, Marketing Director Fairfax, VA

04/2010

- Provided day-to-day maintenance, customization and enhancement to Sensei's Website
- Managed and developed both Sensei and their clients PPC Google Adword campaigns
- Initiated the re-development of Sensei's marketing strategy and re-designed Sensei's marketing portfolio
- Implemented social media communications into Sensei's marketing plan and managed social media properties including: monitoring, posting, and content development
- Developed HTML marketing e-mail blasts campaigns for Sensei's monthly newsletter "Bytes in Brief"

# The Washington Examiner Newspaper, Marketing Analyst & Promotions Specialist 01/2007- 08/2008 Washington, DC

- Crafted the Examiner's sales presentations by evaluating market data, competitor products, our product, and the newspaper industry
- Managed mapping and database applications for sales, which presented customers our distribution relative to their location
- Assisted in the development of B2B sales materials supporting new business efforts (i.e. brochures, advertorials)
- Assist Sales Staff with coordinating marketing functions and presence at events and meetings
- Acted as Marketing Director for a period of five months

### YRCI Recruiting - BearingPoint, Inc., Contracts Specialist Mclean, VA

06/2006 - 01/2007

- Completed due diligence of contract files to determine what documentation was missing.
- Worked on and streamlined the "One globe terminology and hierarchy dB" and completed a report on linking and contract numbering schema errors.
- Employed knowledge and skill with the web based CSAP briefing tool to enter data from prior contract briefs and create a new contract brief.

#### **Education**

BSBA Marketing Communications and Advertising, Western New England University, 2006